Four-leaf clovers

Rehashing old memories

This page is a mess. I'm in the middle of construction, so there's much debris. Please ignore this page for now.

When I was a young child, I used to hunt four-leaf clovers fairly often. I'd look for them next to the parking lot at my elementary school, which is where I found most of mine, but when Summer would take me on yard sale sprees, I'd look for them in other people's yards too. I didn't know what to do with them after finding them, but it was always exciting to find yet another one. It feels like I found hundreds, but that's probably my memory playing tricks on me. I'm certain I found dozens though. I found a half dozen in one sitting sometimes. Summer and Vivian joined in too. I don't think they got into it as much as I did, but they both certainly found them as often as I did when we looked together. At one point, Summer started pressing the specimens we found. I'm not sure if she ever did anything with them after that, but why not give them to her? I wasn't going to do anything with them. They wilted fairly quickly after being plucked. I wasn't going to keep them.

I found at least two or three five-leaf clovers too, which was even more fun. I'd never heard of those before. I never believed the superstition about the four-leaf ones bringing good luck, but I *had* heard the superstition, so I had heard of four-leaf clovers. But five-leafers? No one ever seems to talk about those. At one point, I found a six-leafer and a nine-leafer. I found them in at recess in the middle of the school day though, and by the time school had gotten out, I'd lost them. In retrospect, maybe they were stolen? I don't know. In any case, Summer never believed me that I'd found them.

I found a seven-leafer too at one point. This one was much more bizarre than the others though. I always assumed clovers with more than three leaves were mutants. But this one showed just how mutated it was. It looked outright unhealthy. I mean, it was plenty green and vibrant, but it had leaves growing out of the central vain of other leaves and leaves partly fused with leaves

If I recall, Summer claimed never to have found so many as we - Summer included - had found at the school. It might have been just that we looked more for them there than she'd ever looked for them. Maybe that's not something she'd taken the time to do. In retrospect, that was probably the case, as I was finding them in all sorts of places, not just at the school. However, with them seemingly common there and my thinking they were mutants, it made me wonder about the health of the area. Was all the car exhaust from the school's parking lot we were finding them near harming the clovers, and causing them to mutate? That was my theory at the time. The parking lot only had room for a single row of cars, but you pulled in directly from the street. It was one of the town's main roads, too, so it was a rather busy street. Not the sort of place you want to put a school, if the car exhaust there is enough to cause mutations.

The car exhaust probably wasn't actually causing the mutations, though research does indicate that having more than three leaves in clovers, or rather, leaflets, is indeed a mutation. We're not really sure why it happens though, and it's a decently-common mutation.

Summer actually had some clover-looking plants in her flowerbed when I was growing up. They were larger than clovers by far though, and had different flowers. She called them shamrocks, but I never understood, as I was convinced that shamrocks were just four-leaf clovers. Research these days showed me that shamrocks aren't four-leaf clovers, but just clovers in general. And those plants weren't clovers. I'm not sure what they were though, but they were likely somewhat related to clovers. I think I remember the leaves either being red or having red on them, but I don't rightly recall. They might have been Oxalis tetraphylla, a plant known to resemble clover and have four leaflets. I never really took the time to find out what they might be until I wrote up this page though, so my memory of them is rather faded.

Copyright © 2020 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

How I came to be a Debian user

Rehashing old memories

When I was very young, Summer, my mother, bought a home computer. Home computers were pretty new back then. Probably pretty expensive, too. I mean, home computers these days are still pretty pricey, but they would have been much more so back then, when the technology was still new, and production methods weren't so efficient. As such, I, a small child, was told never to touch the thing. I didn't really know or care why at the time. And as I didn't know much about the thing, I had no real interest in it. I had no idea what power computers held, and they might not have even been good enough yet to be worth my time, in retrospect. What could I even do with the thing? Needless to say, this machine ran Windows. That'll be relevant later.

In school, we started working with computers. Apple had donated a bunch of OS X machines to the school district, so that's what I grew up on: OS X. At some point, I was exposed to Windows. I don't remember the circumstances. But I found it a pain to work with, as I was used to OS X by then. Apple's computer-donation plan had worked well on me. Eventually, my father offered to buy me a laptop. He said he could either get me a brand-new Windows machine or, because they're so much more expensive, a used OS X machine. Needless to say, I went with the Apple laptop. I didn't care if it was used. Everything I owned already was used, so why should my laptop be any different?

This machine didn't hold up well. he hinge was weak, and it started to break. The breaking hinge impacted use of the machine much more than I thought it would, at the time. The screen became increasingly tinted red, so I could barely see anything on it. By applying pressure in just the right places, I could restore enough of the picture to continue using the machine for a while, but even that became diminishing effective over time. I had to go without a computer for years, after that. I later found out that the hinge issue is a common Apple laptop issue. Their hardware looks sleek and fancy, and it certainly costs a lot, but it lacks durability, and isn't worth your money.

There used to be a used computer store closer to my home. Out of luck, Summer and I stopped in there one day because she needed something. I forget what. They were clearing out old Apple desktop machines; the kind where the computer is built into the thick, oddly-shaped monitor. An iMac. These things were way old by this point, but they were exactly what I'd grown up on at school. And they were only $20 USD each. So I bought one. I honestly had no idea just how outdated these things actually were. I hadn't been in school for a while, and hadn't seen the new Apple machines. I had no desk, and had to put it on my dresser. I had no chair, either, and sat on the nearby bed. It hurt my wrists to use the keyboard in such a setup, but at least I had a computer again.

The thing ran OS X 10.4.11. The machine was so old that it couldn't be updated to any later system. I used the thing for a few years, always at the same version, so I still remember the operating system's version number. It's kind of funny. It was a PowerPC machine, and I found that most interesting software either didn't run on PowerPC, or didn't run on systems that old. What really annoyed me about the software that wouldn't run on older operating systems though was that most of it didn't even tell what the cutoff point was numerically. For example, a piece of software might claim to run on "Snow Leopard" or later. What does that even mean? 10.4.11, my system, was part of the range given the code name "Tiger". But how do I compare them? Is "Snow Leopard" earlier or later than "Snow Leopard"? Version code names suck, and there's no good reason to use them. Please, *please*, *please*, always specify things using version numbers, and not those ridiculous code names. You might think it's fine for your use case. It's not. It's definitely not. As an example, Ubuntu's versions are given by Canonical code names with the first letter beginning with the next letter in the order of the English alphabet. So you might think it's easy to compare code names and figure out where they fall in relation to one another. BUT NOT EVERYONE *KNOWS* THAT CANONICAL DOES THIS!! Please don't expect everyone to be in the loop. There are new users, as well as long-time users. Version numbers are *always* easier and more-intuitive to compare.

Summer always got annoyed that I preferred OS X over Windows. But what did she expect? I'd been raised on OS X, and it was so much better of a system. I mean, Apple hardware was apparently garbage, and that's an issue, but OS X was built up from a solid BSD foundation. It wasn't BSD-compatible by any means, but it had that strong, UNIX-like base, making it run a thousand times better than Windows will probably *ever* run. I hadn't been exposed to Windows as a young child, and as she herself has such a hard time adapting to change, she should have very-easily seen how she'd contributed to being a Mac person by making sure I was exposed to OS X and *only* OS X.

I learned the basics of a lot of things on that machine. I got my start in pixel art, for example. I tried a couple different image editors. The GIMP was the one I started with, but it was a major pain to work with. At the time, I thought this the GIMP's fault, but I'd later learn that the GIMP works fantastically on Linux. I think the problem was the X system for OS X. X got ported to OS X, and you had to install X because the GIMP depended on it. I forget what the port was called, but it didn't play nicely with OS X's native graphics system, and if I recall, merely mousing over a window automatically bringing focus to it, making multi-window applications such as the GIMP painful to use. It might have also defocused windows when you move the cursor off of them, but I don't recall for sure. I ended up switching to Seashore rather quickly. It's a dumbed-down image editor that reuses source code from the GIMP. While it has less options than the GIMP, it's also made specifically to run well on OS X, though that's the *only* system it runs on.

I also got started with Web languages, including XHTML and CSS. My first website was hosted on this old iMac, and I used OS X's built-in Apache and PHP instances to do it, at first. These instances were hopelessly entangled with the system though, so when I discovered how outdated my PHP instance was, and that my Apache instance was too old for then-modern PHP, I ended up having to compile and install a second copy of both PHP and Apache, leaving the system-included ones installed but disabled.

I often found my iMac wasn't powerful enough to do the things I wanted it to do. I couldn't even watch videos on it, for example, so when I started taking one of the first MOOCs in the world, the machine wasn't up to the task. By then, I'd gotten a desktop Mac, which I mainly used as a server, but it couldn't connect to Wi-Fi, so it had to live under Summer's desk, where the router was housed. So I typically didn't have access to this machine physically, and it ran headless most of the time. I barely got her to let me use it to take the course, so I wasn't going to be able to get her to let me use it for anything else. At some point, my pibling gave me a pair of old laptops, so I'd have something powerful enough to use, but also Wi-Fi compatible. The catch was that they both ran Windows. *That* wasn't going to happen. So I looked into how to install OS X on them, planning to buy a copy of the system for at least one of the machines. What I found was that due to the wording of the OS X license agreement, installing OS X on non-Apple hardware is illegal! It's possible, and people do it, but Apple makes you agree that you don't own your copy of it, and because they now own it after you agree to that, they can restrict what hardware it can be installed on. I could have done it, and no one would have to know. I would probably have even needed to download a modified copy of the system, just to make it run, meaning that Apple's ridiculous terms would have cost them that money, whether I went with OS X or not. However, it very much felt like Apple was telling me - and everyone else that had non-Apple hardware - that they didn't want us as customers, even of their software. And if Apple didn't even want me, I'd find someone that did.

I'd heard of a system called Linux. I knew pretty much nothing besides the name and that the developers were giving it away gratis. Oh, but also that it wasn't Windows. That was it's most important feature, in my book, regardless of whatever else it was good for. So I tried to find it online Much to my surprise, I found that Linux wasn't a single operating system, but a class of similar operating systems that share most of their code. But each one was a bit different. I tried to figure out which one would work best, but there wasn't any way to see for myself. I eventually had to choose one, and take the plunge. I decided on Ubuntu, of which version 12.04 had just been released. It seemed that the consensus was that this one was user-friendly. I needed a system that I could figure out. When I went to download it, the website was bragging that one of its highly-attractive features was the lack of license keys you have to bother inputting. I saw that obviously, it was taking a jab at Windows. But I'd come from the OS X world, and we didn't have to deal with license keys either. A lack of license keys, while difinitely a very good thing, wasn't a new experience for me.

Installation went well. It was as easy as installing OS X, which I'd done several times in order to wipe my iMac when something went wrong with it. The interface was ... less than ideal. But I could deal. At least I wasn't on Windows. That's what I wasn't able to forget. I'd used one of the laptops without wiping Windows for a few weeks before I had time to look into installing OS X on them and I tried to figure out which Linux distribution to install. Even though I didn't like the interface of this one, not having to deal with the frequent freezes and crashes I'd been dealing with on Windows clearly put this system above the alternative, which was to keep Windows on the machine. I'd committed to Ubuntu, and I was going to make it work. I'd later learn its interface to be called "Unity". And despite Unity's awkwardness, Ubuntu performed literally every feat I needed from my computer, including basic stability, which is something Windows was never able to provide me. It also had a leg up on OS X. To start with, it ran modern software, while my OS X installation had been too old for most modern software. And to sweeten the pot, it came with a package manager that would install whatever I wanted, without my needing to go search the web for it. How cool is that?

About a week later, it dawned on me. I didn't *have* to commit to Ubuntu. It wasn't like I had to buy everything I tried. It wasn't like with each jump to a new Linux distribution, I was having to shell out for another operating system, which I wouldn't be able to afford. I could actually try out my different options, no strings attached. It was a huge turning point for me; it was like an entire world of possibilities had just opened up to me. In my research, I'd learned that Ubuntu was a fork of Debian. Maybe Debian would provide me a better experience. So I installed Debian 6. It seemed to break on me rather easily. I find that really odd though, as Debian's one of the most-stable systems there are, at least these days. Was it really that bad at version 6? I'm not sure what the issue was. Next, I tried Linux Mint. I think it was at version 13, at the time, but I can't say for sure. That seemed to work well enough for a time, but also seemed to have issues. Did something break? Or was it the application menu problems? I don't recall; it's been so long. In any case, I decided to switch again. By this time, I'd discovered the Ubuntu variants, so I went with Xubuntu. That one worked fantastically for me for years. It had everything I'd liked about Ubuntu, but without the unintuitive Unity interface. I'm honestly not sure what version of Xubuntu I started with, but given that it's just Ubuntu with a different set of default packages, it doesn't really matter anyway.

Eventually, I came across the FSF. I found them through one of their licenses, the GNU GPL. I'd seen this license even in the OS X world. Applications such as the GIMP and Seashore were under this license. I'd seen other licenses I'd thought of similarly too, such as the ones Apache and PHP were licensed under. I'd always appreciated the mentality that the developers wanted to allow users to do whatever they liked with the code, so long as they allowed others to do the same with their changes, or in the case of some of these licenses, not even with the restriction that the new developers be as kind as the old developers. This sort of desire to share your efforts with others you don't even know personally always made me feel good, when I ended up installing software with a popup asking me to agree to such a license. And now I'd found an organisation whose sole purpose was to spread such a philosophy. I learned form them that such licensing isn't simply a kind and optional gesture. It's outright mandatory for releasing ethical software. Knowledge, including code, cannot be owned, and copyright law is a blight on our legal system. I switched to Trisquel, an FSF-endorsed distribution. I was an FSF donor, and I should put my efforts where my money was. I tried other FSF-endorsed distributions, but found that gNewSense's software was too old, Dragora's installer didn't seem to function, and the installers for the other FSF-endorsed distributions were too difficult to use. By this time, my philosophy about installation was that you shouldn't need a set of instructions to read outside the installer, as your machine would be tied up with the installer itself, with no way to search the Web for the instructions. Therefore, command-line-based installers were not acceptable for general users, only for advanced users. I also believed that I needed to run a system fit for people of any skill level, so I could recommend that system when opportunities arrised.

I later learned that the FSF was full of garbage, and even contradicted the philosophy I'd learned form them. In fact, the philosophy I'd learned form them wasn't even the one they'd tried to teach me. The FSF is only concerned about the practical aspect of freedom. They don't care about the principle of the matter. As such, they only care about freedom when it comes to software. If you don't have access to the source code, you don't know what the software is having your computer do. If you don't have permission to modify the source code, you don't control your own computer. And if you're not allowed to redistribute your changes, the general public can't have dependable and trustworthy software. However, the FSF doesn't care about media freedom, and actually actively oppose it by releasing non-free non-software. Media freedom is important too though. Ideas cannot be owned, and when media copyrights restrict what we can do with our media, it's censorship. Sure, we can control our computers if we have free software. But without free media, it's control of our minds and our self-expression that we lack. How is that any less important? So I stopped donating to the FSF, and wrote them off. I switched away from Trisquel, too. I couldn't find a single statement on their website saying they had any interest in keeping non-free non-software out of their distribution, and keeping non-free non-software out of distributions was specifically mentioned by the FSF as not being a requirement for their endorsement. You know who *did* make such a commitment though? Debian.

So I went back to Debian. Debian and the FSF were in disagreement as to what constitutes a free operating system. The Debian team was of the opinion that by just saying something wasn't a part of their distribution, it wasn't a part of their distribution. It was as simple as that. The FSF believed though that if the non-free components were hosted on the same servers as the main system, and if the non-free components were documented in the same official manual as the main system, they were a part of the distribution. Personally, I disagreed with both sides. You can't make something magically not a part of your system just by saying it's not. At the same time though, multiple things can be hosted on the same server without them being the same thing. Official and unofficial things can even be hosted on a server together. And the documentation? Seriously? The system's documentation is completely irrelevant to what is actually a part of the system and not. However, synaptic was a part of Debian, and this wasn't denied by anyone. And synaptic treated three repos as special; they could be turned on and off vie checkboxes. These were the main, contrib, and non-free repos. Synaptic allows you to add arbitrary repos, and that's just fine, but because these three were given special treatment, they were, in my eyes, obviously all a part of Debian. So Debian wasn't fully free. It was the closest I could find though, and because all the non-free stuff was quarantined in optional repositories, it was easy to run a fully-free Debian instance. Another disagreement between the Debian developers and the FSF though was an incredibly deciding factor for me: not just the definition of what is and is not a part of the distribution, but what is and is not free. Debian's definition treated all components as needing identical freedoms. The FSF arbitrarily singles out the things they believe freedom is useful for, and strategically don't require freedom for things such as manuals, so they can insert their propaganda into them and be sure that propaganda, which is an anti-feature because of its unremovability, cannot be removed. Seriously, I'd happily have their propaganda if it wasn't forced. It's just like having software that can be modified, except that you're not allowed to take out the license key verification or something. You claim it to be free software, but it clearly isn't because you can't remove the noxious part. It's the same with GFDL-licensed works. And while the FSF refuses to see that, the Debian developers do, and they don't include these noxious manuals in their distribution. Between Debian quarantining non-free components and making a commitment to treating all components, not just software, as needing to be free, Debian was a system I could install without fear that I might accidentally bring in a non-free component via some dependency chain. So that's what I did. Debian became the only system I'd allow on my machines.

The Debian team later fixed my main freedom-related complaint, the special treatment of those three repositories. I mean, main obviously still gets special treatment in that when you install the system, the system's already configured to use that repo. But the other two are no longer something I'd consider a part of the system. Debian has become, in my eyes, a free system. Well, mostly. Debian accepts licenses that disallow modification of the source code so long as the source can be distributed along with patches. From a standpoint of principle, I consider these pieces of software to be non-free, as they disallow modification of the source code. But from practical standpoint, these pieces of software are "free enough", and it's worth ignoring the bizarre licensing terms just to have an operating system I can use.

So that's where I am today. I use Debian because it's one of two free operating systems I know of. I also use PureOS though, which is a fork of Debian, because it came preinstalled on my Librem 15. I've found no indication that Purism specifically makes an effort to keep non-free non-software out of the repo, but there doesn't seem to be a reason why they'd add it to the Debian base they're starting with. Trisquel, on the other hand, is derived from Ubuntu, which is known to include non-free components. And as Purism is working to develop free hardware specifications, it seems reasonable to trust them for the time being. Their laptops are a pain to work with because of the lack of mouse buttons, but they're clearly trying to do good in the world.

Copyright © 2019 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Gender, sex, and sexuality

Rehashing old memories

Summer, my mother, thought I had a crush on a girl back in elementary school. I didn't. I had no interest in her. I guess I thought she was pretty, but more in an I'd-like-to-look-like-that-too sort of way. She was Mexican, and had a dark, Latin skin. I'm pale and ugly. I guess I've always thought Latin skin looks nice. My pale, white skin doesn't look great, but at the same time, lack skin is a bit too dark for me. Latins have a nice balance; a mid-tone brown. Don't get me wrong, I'm not racist and don't really care what colour of skin you have. It's your personality and your intelligence that matter. But that doesn't mean I don't have a visual preference, and I think Latins have the nicest skin colour. This girl also had a pretty name, one I haven't heard used elsewhere. It could be a common name in Mexico, I don't even know, but where I live, she seems to have a unique name. Anyway, Summer hassled me about this girl for a couple decades. I always denied having a crush on her, but that only made her hassle me harder. She just couldn't get it through her thick skull that she could have been wrong about my feelings for her. Or maybe, she believed me, but thought my reaction to her hassling was funny. I found it highly frustrating though. To claim I would have a crush on anyone was to question a core aspect of my being: my asexuality.

It was in late elementary school or early middle school that I learned about sex and it being where babies come from. I thin kit was in my final year of elementary school though. I knew right away that that wasn't for me. I decided I'd die a virgin. I didn't have the word for it yet - asexuality - but the idea of sex thoroughly repulsed me. As a male, it was my job to stick my penis inside a female? Gross. Why would I want to put any part of my body inside any part of someone else? It'd be fine, I guess, if it was my hands. But anything else was off the table. And I couldn't understand why a female would allow a male to stick any part of his body inside hers. I wouldn't want someone sticking body parts inside me!

As I understood more about the process, I realised it would be terrible for me to reproduce anyway. I was a genetically-inferior specimen. I'd inherited bad genes from both my parents. My mother has weak teeth and poor memory. My father has weak teeth and eczema. There's a history of cancer and heart disease on both sides. Wouldn't the human race be stronger if those of us with bad DNA simply chose not to reproduce? I would never advocate forcing others not to reproduce, and I'd never advocate genocide of such people the way some dictators have done. But if it was willing, wouldn't refraining from passing on bad genes be the noble thing to do? I couldn't make the same mistake my parents had made. I just wouldn't allow myself to inflict my genetic problems on someone else. Much later in life, I came to the realisation that it doesn't even matter how bad my genetics are. All deaths are caused by the creation of new lives. Even if I had perfect genetics, if I created children, I'd be necessarily causing those children to one day die. Their deaths would be directly my fault, and I couldn't live with that. I'd also be indirectly responsible for the deaths of my later descendants too, as while I wouldn't have chosen to create the later descendants, I could have still prevented their creation by not creating my direct children.

I guess soon after that is when I started imagining myself with a vagina. I never wanted to use it for sex, but thought I'd rather have a vagina than a penis. I guess I told Summer about that, though I don't remember actually doing that. At some point, I learned there was a surgical option, but I never considered it a possibility. I didn't know about the hormonal treatments that are also needed, and I wasn't aware that the procedure isn't perfect, but I feared surgery. I sometimes wished longingly that I'd been born a female, but figured there was no feasible way for me to correct the problem.

I've always hated my birth name. My hated my birth given name, but my birth middle name was even worse. I didn't really understand until around 2017 why I had such a problem with these names. They were just too masculine. I guess I should have realised a lot sooner, given that I didn't even want to be male.

In high school, I suppose I found one girl physically attractive. It wasn't a strong attraction, and I definitely made sure to keep it a secret. I went over a decade without admitting it; this page here is probably my first admission of it. I found sexual attraction to be a shameful thing. I mean, it's an instinct that serves for reproduction, and nothing more. And I've always viewed reproduction as something I should avoid at all costs. I never attended any school dances, as I never had anyone I'd want to go with. Not even the girl I was attracted to. I mean, I thought she was pretty, but I never once even wanted to spend any time with her. It was never like that. She was just a girl I shared a couple classes with. If I *had* wanted a relationship with her though, I would have no doubt kept that fact to myself and definitely would have refrained from acting on it.

I don't recall when, but at some point, Summer took me to a doctor to have my testosterone level checked. I was too afraid of Summer to resist the test, but it scared me because of its implications. What would be the point of getting my testosterone level checked if there wasn't a plan to *act* on it? I always told myself I'd resist treatment though. I'd refuse testosterone supplements tooth and nail. I didn't want to be manlier. I thought being manlier would be stupid. I didn't like the way men seemed to think, though I wasn't yet aware that I wasn't a man. In retrospect, if Summer pushed the issue, I'm not sure I'd have the emotional strength to resist for long. She tore me down so much that I didn't really have the strength to resist much. But if they were taken orally, I could have kept the pills in my mouth and spit them out later, so while some of it would have still gotten into my system, most of it wouldn't. Sure enough, the test came back saying I had low testosterone. But Summer never even seemed to seriously bring up the issue. I mean, before the test, she said we could get a testosterone supplement prescribed if my testosterone was low, but though I never verbally said anything about it, she never brought it up after the test. Maybe she read my body language and saw how appalled I was by the idea. I just don't know. I don't remember well enough how I even acted when the idea came up.

I had a gay friend in high school. I didn't find him attractive in any way, but he seemed nice as a person, mostly. And my only complaints had nothing to do with his sexuality. I've never had a problem with gays. I figured anal sex was no worse than vaginal sex; both were gross. I guess I didn't think about lesbians. What they did had nothing to do with me because I had a penis. They used to telephone me frequently though, and we'd spend hours talking. I always found the experience to be wearisome, but I didn't know how to tell them that I didn't want to talk. I certainly enjoyed speaking with them in person, but I've always hated telephone calls. Summer usually saved me from these calls after we'd talked for about an hour, so the calls didn't get even longer. She'd say we were tying up the line, and she was usually waiting for a call from her sibling, and this was something I could easily tell my friend without feeling guilty. Really, it's not me saying I've got to go, it's Summer! Summer said he must be sexually attracted to me. I explained that he knew I was asexual, so he wouldn't try something with me. She didn't buy it. And in retrospect, she was probably right. This boy knew what I was, but thought he could change me.

Once high school ended, I started work at a restaurant. There, I soon got stationed as one of the two main dough-makers, the other being the assistant manager at the time. We got along great, but they always said that I must be repressed, due to not believing in asexuals. I guess they were right about me. That said, repression saved me from a lot of garbage I'd otherwise have to deal with from Summer, and I'm not sure how I would have possibly gotten by back then if not repressed. But they weren't right about everyone. Asexuals do very much exist. Anyway, they thought I just needed to try sex, and assumed me to be heterosexual. They said that they'd been like me until a girl'd raped them, then they found they actually enjoyed the experience. I think "rape" was an exaggeration, to be honest, especially the way they described it. Well, maybe not. They said no, and the girl pushed them onto the bed and said it'd be fine. They resisted somewhat, though it didn't sound like they resisted a whole lot. At the time, it didn't seem like rape to me, as there wasn't really any force involved, but in retrospect, there was also no consent, so if their description was accurate, it was indeed rape.

At the restaurant, one of the girls working there kept trying to date me. I kept declining, and explaining that I was asexual, but they didn't really stop until they quit working there. Later, they stopped by and were pregnant. At that point, I realised I'd dodged a major bullet. Like most people, they were the type that wanted children. Assuming they could even get me in bed (which would be unlikely at that point in my life) and there'd been an accident (there's absolutely no way I would ever impregnate someone intentionally), she'd probably have the child. She wouldn't be on my side, and likely wouldn't be fond of the idea of abortion. I might be able to talk her into it, but I somehow doubt that'd go over well.

I also had a customer once tell me I had pretty eyes. I really didn't know how to respond to that, but it made me uncomfortable. Keep in mind though that I was still repressed at this time in my life.

At some point after high school, I started taking online courses, not worth any credit, in my free time. One course I took was on the medical difference between sex and gender, and what the differences between genders is. In some ways, this paved the path I now walk. I understand that there's legitimately a difference, one that even medical science recognises, so I don't buy into crap people try to serve about how I should act like a man because I'm male. Being male doesn't make me a man! However, this course didn't cover everything. It didn't cover the non-binary gender, or even the intersex sex. It focused on the binary, and that messed up my thoughts about myself for years. In particular, the course mentioned how men have a tendency to directly say what they mean, which is something that I do. It mentioned that women tend to be more subtle, then expect you to pick up on clues. At that point, I figured that if that was the cost of being a woman, not only must I already be a man, but I didn't even *want* to be a woman. Sublety has a place, and can be a very good thing. But it's obnoxious and counterproductive when someone won't tell you directly what they want from you. For a time, I accepted the place society wanted to box me into: the role of a man. Sure, I was never into sports, weight-lifting, working on vehicles, tools, or other manly things. But at least I said what I meant, and that was very important to me. Of course, I later learned there's isn't a hard line between being a man and being a woman. Some of us are in-between, and that's fine too. Not being a woman didn't mean I must be a man.

I'm not sure where to stick this in, but I used to think girls should stop dressing in girl clothes because it's socially acceptable for them to wear boy clothes and the separate clothing style is ridiculous. I thought this from near the beginning, all the way up until I understood that it wasn't the girls that needed to change. It was the boys. I now understand though that it's the boys that need to let go of the nonsense and dress however they like. It'd be so much better to remove ridiculous limitations on those that are under them, not impose those same limitations on everyone else. Thankfully, this seems to be the way society is moving.

Copyright © 2019 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Gifts

Rehashing old memories

Summer has always had bizarre attitudes when it came to gifts and gift-giving. It was also never safe to expose what you actually cared about to her when I was a child because she'd weaponize it later and use it against you. Because of these things, and because she lacks the empathy needed to understand what people actually like, she tended to give really bad gifts. It was to the point that I asked her not to give me anything whenever she'd ask what I wanted. She'd never accept that though, as when she wanted to give gifts, she felt she had a right to, even though when her friends give *her* gifts when she asked them not to, she'll drop the unwanted gifts back off at their door. She's never really been able to see that unwanted gifts are unwanted gifts if she's on the giving end. I also had to talk my siblings into not giving me anything I actually wanted, as that too would open up windows for her to attack me through.

I found one particular aspect of her bizarre gift-giving attitudes particularly noteworthy: she hated cash being given, and would prefer just about anything be given ahead of cash, even if she was neither the giver nor the receiver and the receiver preferred cash. At one point, I finally bought my first domain name. With it, I finally had something I could claim I wanted as a gift without it being easily weaponized and that I actually had a use for: domain name renewals. These proved problematic for Summer though. She didn't like them, because the best way to get me what I wanted was to hand over cash. Vanessa actually tried doing this one one occasion. However, Summer insisted that Vanessa give *her* the cash, then instead give me a hand-written certificate that was "good for" a domain name renewal. Except this certificate couldn't be redeemed with any registrar, and could only be redeemed with the giver, Vanessa. So had I ever redeemed it, Vanessa would then have had to pay double, once to me and once to Summer. And in the end, Vanessa would still have ended up handing me cash, so it didn't even bypass the cash-handover that Summer detested. Of course, I felt that redeeming such a certificate would be the same as begging for a gift, so even if it didn't mean Vanessa paid twice, I wouldn't've done it. Such certificates aren't gifts, as far as I'm concerned, but invitations to beg for gifts. I honestly don't know what Summer was hoping to achieve here. I somehow don't think she was trying to pull money out of Vanessa or steal the gift, even though that's what she ended up doing. I think it's just another expression of her insanity, her lack of empathy, and her tendency to project her own thoughts onto others.

On the topic of certificates, she once gave me an actual certificate to visit a raptor centre. I'm not sure what the deal was with that. I'd never even expressed an interest in birds. I mean, I know I expressed false interests around her at times either to throw her off so she couldn't properly attack me with the things I did care about or to make her feel good by expressing an interest in her own interests, but I never thought to do such a thing with birds. They just never caught my attention much, so this gift was completely out of the blue. And then, there was the fact that she made herself so unapproachable. We children couldn't really ask her to take us anywhere without being met with backlash, so I could never ask her to take me to this raptor centre, which I had no idea where was. And it would have cost to get in, because the certificate was only valid for one person. There was no feasible way to use this certificate as a child, and nothing ever became of it. I kept it for years until I lost it, probably in one of our moves, just to look at it every once in a while and marvel at what a bizarre gift it was and wonder what she was possibly thinking.

Another thing Summer has always done is either mention that she's going to get you something, or outright ask if you'd like it, then when you decline, get it for you anyway and wonder why you aren't happy with it. Like, seriously. If you say you don't want it, why does she think that you do? Again, I get that I've always had to hide my true interests to defend myself from her until I moved out. However, I'm not sure how much of that she understood was going on. And if she did know, one of two things would be the case: either I had no interest in it and didn't want it or I did have an interest in it and didn't want it used against me. If the former, having it wouldn't really be of benefit, and if the latter (which never happened because she didn't have a clue what I actually liked), having it would be torture. Either way, I don't win. Either way, it's a terrible gift. If she was going to give unwanted gifts, she could at least choose gifts that she hadn't been directly told were things I didn't want. It wasn't just me, either. My siblings noticed the same thing happening with them when they'd express disinterest in things. It kind of makes me wonder if Summer was doing it on purpose. If she was though, she was very good at hiding it.

Copyright © 2020 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Suicide

Rehashing old memories

When I was younger, I always felt like I wasn't supposed to exist. That I was a mistake of nature. Later, I learned how people are created, and I knew immediately that I was never to breed. My genes were flawed, and it was my responsibility to refrain from passing them on to the next generation. I've never believed that people should be forced not to breed. However, I believed back then that if those of us with genetic issues and flaws were to willingly weed ourselves out of the gene pool, the human species would be stronger for it.

I suppose my thoughts on the matter have changed, though not in a way that changes the end result. I'm not a mistake of nature. The simple fact is that to make mistakes, you have to have intent. Nature is chaotic, and has no intent. Life just tries to replicate itself. Usually. There are a few of us that intentionally break the cycle, but the majority of us either breed or die before we can. But with life necessarily comes death, so to inflict someone with life is to inflect them also with death, and I could never do that to anyone. So I still won't be breeding. You're supposed to *love* your children. Inflicting death on them isn't a very loving act. The most loving thing I can do for them is to not create them. I think I have the right to make use of what life I have, and exist as long as I'm willing and able to, but I have no right to inflict life and death on others.

As a child though, when I thought I wasn't meant to be, I was a bit suicidal at times, especially after Summer had just thrown one of her tantrums and gone off on me about how terrible I was. She tore me down though, and made me weak. I didn't have the courage to end myself quickly. Instead, I repeatedly tried to starve myself to death, but within a day or two, the sharp edge of her words would have worn off a bit, and my fear of death would kick in more. So I always backed down before I'd even gotten close to dying. At one point, I actually ran away from home one night after she'd screamed at me about something that wasn't even my fault. I figured I'd just starve to death somewhere were no one would have to deal with it. I was out on the porch when she'd yelled at me though, and had no shoes or coat on because I didn't expect to be out there long, and I didn't really feel like I could head in to get them. It was a miserable hour or so before I gave up, being as weak as she made me, and I returned home. In retrospect, I should have stayed gone. I shouldn't've tried to starve myself, but instead, gotten myself found. I could have ended up in a foster home or something. It wouldn't be ideal, but it'd likely be better than where I was, and I could have begun my emotional healing a couple decades earlier than I did in the end, back when there was much less damage to heal from.

Copyright © 2020 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Telephony

Rehashing old memories

If you've read a lot of my journal entries, you've probably been under the distinct impression that I can't stand telephones. This impression would be absolutely correct. I have a deep-seated distaste for telephones that goes way back to my childhood. I still find telephone calls to be rather inconvenient, but I go to far greater inconveniences and hassles just to avoid telephone calls because I can't stand how ridiculous the telephone system is set up on a technical level. Your chat handle isn't a human-meaningful sting. It's a number. but it's not a machine-meaningful number either, and has to be looked up in lookup tables before the telephone call can be routed. It's the worst of both worlds. I'd put up with telephones if they at least used DNS so proper, human-meaningful, and sub-nameable strings could be used. But even if that were the case, I'd definitely not take delight in taking or placing telephone calls. And I especially wouldn't appreciate people pestering me with telephone calls or SMS when I was out and about. Below are a few stories of my past past dealings with telephones. I don't think any of them really shaped my opinion of the technology, but they show that my distaste for telephones is nothing new.

I remember Summer used to go on outings with Vivian, searching for hidden objects using GPS coordinates, and leave me behind. I was never the golden child. I asked to come along, but never got a chance to. Eventually, she picked up the pace, and would get dozens in one go. Vivian could do that, as she'd worked her way up to that point with Summer, but I didn't want to go anymore, as on the odd occasion in which she's take me, which she started doing rarely, I had to jump from not doing any of the hunts to suddenly being stuck on a trip where I had to do tonnes of them. I hadn't built up the stamina nor the patience for it. I couldn't stand it when she finally took me, so I stopped asking, and didn't go often. But summer would phone home for whatever reason, often to give pointless information that wasn't relevant or useful to anything. And while I heard the telephone ring, I ignored it. It wasn't my telephone line and wasn't my problem. And I didn't want to deal with telephone calls. But then Vivian snitched on me, and told Summer I always ignored the telephone. After that, Summer made me always go listen to the answering machine if she was out and the telephone rang. If it was her, I was required to answer. I could hear the telephone from just about anywhere in the house, but to make out who was calling, I had to run to the room the telephone was in. I hated being a slave to that infernal device.

When cellphones (actual cellular telephones, not these so-called "smartphones" that aren't telephones at all, but pocket computers) were first coming out, Summer was vocal about how terrible they were, and how they were a blight on society. People would use them while driving, putting people in jeopardy, et cetera. And I don't recall for sure, but she might have thought that people don't need to be tethered to everyone else when they're out and about. How clingy. But maybe I'm just projecting, because I don't like people being able to pester me no matter where I am. If I'm not at home, you can wait until I get home to pester me. Seriously. But then she got a cellphone. And she liked it. If I recall, she got it for emergency situations while she was out in the woods looking for hidden objects with her GPSr, but I honestly don't remember for sure. And that's when she hated on SMS. It was a lazy way to communicate, not to mention that it was expensive. And her friends were inconsiderate. She kept telling them not to text message her, because she got charged for it, and to call instead. But they wouldn't listen, and she had to foot the bill. She wonders why I hate SMS, but honestly, she hated SMS too and was very vocal about it. I don't hate it for the same reasons, and I don't hate it because of her, but it's odd she doesn't consider that she might be the reason I hate it; that she rubbed off on me before changing her mind. But yeah, she kept telling her friends not to SMS her, and kept telling them about how it cost her money to receive these messages whether she wanted them or not, and how her carrier wouldn't let her block them. She's always been a Verizon customer, and we all know how Verizon screws over their customers every chance they get. Eventually, she gave in and sprung for the unlimited SMS plan, which cost more than what she wanted to pay, but less than what she was getting charged because of her inconsiderate friends. After that, SMS started to grow on her. These days, she seems to think it's the best thing ever, and it seems to be her favourite way to communicate. If you try to reach her another way, such as via email, she tends to get a bit weird about it. Now, she doesn't understand how someone could not want a cellphone, not want to carry one everywhere, not want to communicate via telephone call, or not enjoy sending and receiving SMS messages. I've never known her to have a problem with placing or taking telephone calls, and she seemed to like that method of communication even when landlines were the only telephony option, but the rest of that? She was opposed to all of it at one point, yet lacks the empathy now to see why anyone might not enjoy conforming to this new societal norm.

When I was in high school, I had a gay friend who really liked to talk via telephone. I got enough of them during the school day, and while I'd be happy to have them over at my place or happy to go over to theirs if Summer wasn't against my visiting or taking visitors, dealing with them via telephone was always a huge drag. And they liked to talk for over an hour at time. They tended only to get off once Summer complained we were tying up the line and made me get off the telephone. I always found that to be a huge relief; the call was finally over. These telephone calls were probably the most boring thing I had to deal with. Summer thought this friend had a crush on me. And in retrospect, she was probably right. But I had no sexuality back then, and was completely oblivious to that sort of thing. Even now, I'm pretty oblivious to it. And if you're trying to woo me, making me sit on hour-long telephone calls is no way to do it. I can't stand telephone calls, and the longer they are, the worse I find them to be.

Summer tried to get Vivian and I to carry cellphones. Actual cellphones, not the so-called "smartphones" that would be popular later on. Vivian carried hers. I'm not sure if she actually wanted it, and with how over-controlling Summer is, Vivian was never able to use it as she liked and to call or be called by who she liked, but she carried it like a dutiful child. I, on the other hand, rejected the idea of carrying a telephone before we'd even gotten the things. Summer tried to push a bit, but saw I wasn't budging. She replaced the landline with a cellphone, but that telephone was still considered to be the home telephone for as long as we had it, except at least for a time later, she considered it to somehow be mine. She tried again to get me to carry it at that time, and her lover at the time tried to push as well. They almost had me, until they tried to call it "my" phone. At that point, I went back to rejecting it with full force. I was reluctant to carry it at all, but I certainly wasn't going to put up with them considering such an infernal device to be my own. And if I never used, touched, wanted, or chose to have the device, how could it possibly be mine? If I recall, I first tried getting them to stop calling it mine, but when they wouldn't, I took the only countermeasure available to me.

Later, I came to understand that the term "smartphone" was a misnomer. These devices aren't telephones at all, but full-fledged computers, albeit weak ones. They are configured and equipped to handle telephony, but at one point, so was my laptop. That didn't make my laptop a telephone either. Soon after I came to this understanding through the Replicant project, Summer started talking about trying to get me and Vivian on iPhones. Vivian didn't go for that. She said it wouldn't be of any use to her, and that the basic flip-phone she had would suffice. I'm not sure if she barely tolerated the flip-phone and certainly didn't want to have to deal with more or if the flip-phone was really something she wanted. Either way, I had a different take on things. The iPhone was obviously useless to me. But Summer wanted me on her mobile plan, so maybe I could make use of that with a different device. I researched which devices functioned with Replicant, and found none of them were compatible with her CDMA-based carrier. I started researching other plans from other carriers, which I planned to pay for myself, and started leaving pamphlets for them around the house to hint to Summer. I talked to her directly about my search for a good plan, but she didn't really seem to take it seriously. I thought seeing the pamphlets might get her to see that I was serious. It didn't. I decided upon the GT-i9300, and sat on that decision for a while. Finally, one night, I talked to her about my decision to get a GT-i9300 and a which carrier I'd chosen. She asked questions, but didn't object like I thought she would. It turns out it was because she still hadn't taken me seriously.

I ordered the device and bought the SIM card in person, and when Summer found out, she was pissed off. She asked why I hadn't talked to her about it first. I had though. When the device arrived, I ended up carrying it around the house without installing the system for a bit because I wasn't sure what Summer was going to do next, and I thought I might have to try to return it or something. She begrudgingly let me keep it though, and I got the thing set up.

I don't remember how it came up, but she mentioned SMS on my device, so I told her my device didn't use SMS, and used email instead. I didn't tell her this, but I'd disabled the SMS application, which was present on the device and at that point could be disabled. In later Replicant versions, it wouldn't be possible to disable this application through the main application-disabling interface for built-in applications that you can't outright uninstall, and you'd have to install a root-access-using application to do that for you. At this point though, disabling it was a breeze, and dropped it from the application list without hassle. And I didn't want to deal with SMS. with email, I could use a full-sized keyboard if I was at home, but still send messages when I was out when I needed to. It was the best of both worlds. There was absolutely zero reason for me to randomly start using SMS just because I now had a mobile. I'd been using her carrier's SMS gateway to email her my work schedule to her SMS box, where she preferred to receive it, for quite a while by this point. I sent her the schedule as I usually did, but this time using the mobile's email client, and she got pissed off. She claimed that I wasn't sending it via SMS because I was trying to hide my telephone number from her, which she had not even asked for. If she wanted it, all she'd have to do is ask. I reminded her that my device didn't use SMS, and gave her the number. I don't recall if I emailed it to her or spoke the number, but either way, she now had it. I told her she could call me, but SMS messages wouldn't get through, so to continue sending SMS messages to my email address.

She later tried to message me as she often did, and wasn't happy her messages weren't getting through. We sat and tried to debug. One thing I decided to try was sending messages in the other direction. She hadn't missed any of my messages yet that I'd been aware of, and I wanted to be sure nothing had changed on that front. It's a good thing I tried that. She said the message got through, but on the wrong message thread. There should have only been one that conversed with me. It turns out she had intentionally started sending messages to my SMS box. I wasn't getting the messages because she hadn't listened to me any of the times I'd told her the device didn't do SMS messaging, and instead used email. Even if she thought she somehow knew better than me about the availability or lack-of-availability of SMS on my device, she knew very well that I preferred email on my end. I didn't send to her email inbox, as she didn't like that, and sent to her preferred inbox, her SMS inbox. There was no good reason for her not to return the favour. I'm glad to this day that I'd disabled the SMS application for a couple reasons. First, I didn't receive any of those messages. I didn't have to be bothered by them just because Summer wanted to be a pain. Second, I was able to hand the device to her right away without any further configuration, and *show* her that there was no SMS icon in the application menu. There was no way she was going to think to go into the settings on an operating system she wasn't familiar with to look for a disabled SMS application when I was claiming there not to be one at all. What really gets me though is that she was trying to force SMS on me, when I clearly didn't want it. I don't think she remembered when her friends were forcing it on her. It wasn't okay when they did it, and wasn't okay when she did it.

Copyright © 2019 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.